# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hi everyone, I'm Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
Today I'll share the recipe of an everyday dish
# 醋烧鲈鱼
Vinegar braised bass
# 首先我们准备鲈鱼1条（约750克）
First, prepare a bass (around 750g)
# 将鱼鳞去除之后破开鱼肚
Remove the fish scale and cut the belly open
# 去掉内脏和鱼鳃清洗干净备用
Remove the insides and fish gill and rinse it
# 同学们也可以选用鲤鱼草鱼或者鲫鱼
You can also use carp, grass carp, or crucian carp
# 下一步开始改刀
Now cut the fish
# 首先我们将鲈鱼切上一字花刀
First we cut the fish in this pattern
# 刀口不能太宽否则容易烧烂
You need to keep your knife straight down or else the fish will fall apart in the wok
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next start preparing minor ingredients
# 准备猪肥油1小块切成颗粒备用（约35克）
Prepare a small piece of pork fat and dice it (around 35g)
# 准备大蒜和生姜各25克切成小粒备用
Prepare garlic and ginger (25g each) and dice them
# 碗中加入八角1颗
Add a star anise to the bowl
# 加入桂皮几小块
Add some cinnamon
# 加入香叶1小片
Add a bay leaf
# 加入小葱头几根切碎备用
Add a few cutted scallions
# 最后加入适量的干辣椒剪成小节备用
Finally add some dried chili pepper cut in pieces
# 下一步开始制作
Next start cooking
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入宽油
When it's heated, add Kuan You
# 然后开大火烧开将油温烧至6成热
Then turn to high heat until the oil boils to 150 degrees
# 油温6成热之后转小火准备炸鱼
When the oil is heated, turn to low heat and fry the fish
# 鱼下锅之前先加入适量的玉米淀粉拍打均匀
Before putting the fish into the wok, spread corn starch evenly on the surface
# 这一步的目的是防止水分流失将鱼炸得太干
This is to make sure the fish doesn't become too dry
# 然后捏着鲈鱼尾巴下锅浸炸3分钟
Then hold the tail and fry the fish for 3 minutes
# 这一步的目的是将鲈鱼表面炸至金黄酥脆
This is to fry until the surface is golden and crispy
# 中途需要将油均匀地淋在鱼身上面
You need to pour the oil on the fish evenly midway
# 3分钟之后将鲈鱼捞出备用
Take the fish out after 3 minutes
# 不喜欢油炸的同学也可以用少量的油直接煎
If frying isn't your style, you can pan-fry it with much less oil
# 热油倒出之后下一步开始烧汁
Pour out the hot oil and start making the sauce
# 将锅烧热之后加入适量的底油
Heat up the wok and add some base oil
# 油温4成热之后加入准备好的所有料头翻炒1分钟
When the oil reaches 100 degrees, add all minor ingredients and stir-fry for a minute
# 这一步必须爆出猪油和将料头炒香
This is to bring out the flavor of the pork fat and minor ingredients
# 1分钟之后加入蚝油5克
After one minute, add 5g of oyster sauce
# 加入晒醋10克
Add 10g of vinegar
# 加入料酒10克
Add 10g of Chinese cooking wine
# 加入生抽酱油10克
Add 10g of light soy sauce
# 翻炒均匀之后加入适量的清水开大火烧开
Mix it up, add some water, and turn to high heat until it boils
# 大火烧开之后开始调味
After it boils, add more flavor
# 锅中加入适量的食用盐（约2克）
Add some salt to the wok (around 2g)
# 加入白糖2勺（4克）
Add two teaspoons of sugar (4g)
# 加入胡椒粉1勺（约1克）
Add one teaspoon of ground pepper (around 1g)
# 加入鸡精1勺（约1.5克）
Add one teaspoon of chicken essence (around 1.5g)
# 加入老抽3克调色
Add 3g of dark soy sauce for the color
# 最后加入炸好的鲈鱼下锅转小火烧15分钟
Finally add the fried bass to the wok and braise for 15 minutes at low heat
# 同学们烧鱼可以不用翻动只需要浇上热汤即可
You don't need to flip it because you can just pour the hot soup on top
# 15分钟之后将鲈鱼捞出摆盘
Take the bass out after 15 minutes and decorate the plate
# 然后将汤汁中的料头捞出
Then remove minor ingredients from the wok
# 下一步开始勾芡
Next start making the sauce
# 锅中加入少许的水淀粉勾成薄芡
Add some water starch to the wok
# 勾好芡之后再加入现剁的姜末
Then add some minced ginger
# 再加入适量的明油
Then add some Ming You
# 最后均匀地淋在鱼身上面即可上菜
Finally spread the sauce on the fish and it's ready
# 一道非常美味的醋烧鲈鱼就制作完成
We've finished making a delicious vinegar braised bass
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，醋和酒精类似，烧得时间越长挥发得越多
# 第二，加醋烧鱼可以软化鱼刺，此做法更适合烹制刺多的鱼
# 第三，最后起锅前加入适量的姜末可以增加不一样的鲜味
# 醋烧鲈鱼的技术总结完毕
Now, let's summarize the techniques
First, vinegar is like alcohol, the longer you heat it the more likely it'll evaporate
Secondly, adding vinegar softens the fish bones, meaning that this is suitable for fish with lots of bones
Thirdly, adding some minced ginger at the last step enhances the umami flavor
These are all the techniques I'd like to share